COLLINS EFFAH

+23355 528 8029 | ceffah012@gmail.com | Kumasi, Ghana – West Africa

Summary

I am an experienced and dependable professional with a track record of efficiently completing tasks in various settings. I have diverse experience and skills in software engineering (web apps), cybersecurity, and cloud computing. I have strong collaboration and networking abilities to enhance productivity and drive business operations positively.

Skills

Effective Communication | Problem-solving | Time Management | Leadership

Experience

Software Engineer (NSP) - 08/2024 – Current

Kumasi Technical University (KsTU), Kumasi, Ghana

My team is the mastermind behind the university's software suite. We design, develop, deploy, and maintain the various software the university community uses.

AmaliTech - 06/2024 – 09/2024

I developed a file server with Django. The file server project makes it possible to manage and distribute files efficiently.

Web Administrator (Part-Time) - 07/2024 - Current

Mixtech Ltd, Sunyani, Ghana

I design, implement, deploy, and manage web applications

IT Training Instructor (Intern) - 09/2022 – 11/2022

Community ICT Center, Nkoranza, Ghana

I was responsible for facilitating programming (coding) workshops for high students.

I trained a good number of students.

Education and Training

HND Computer Science, 10/2021 - 08/2024

Kumasi Technical University (KsTU)

NABPTEX | Computer Technology, 09/2016 - 06/2019

Nkoranza Technical Institute (NTI)

Portfolios

- www.linked.com/in/ceffah
- https://github.com/YawEffah

Certifications

- Certified Cloud Practitioner, Amazon Web Services (AWS), 05/2024
- Certified in Cybersecurity, International Information System Security Certification Consortium (ISC2), 02/2024
- Introduction to Cybersecurity, Cisco Networking Academy, 06/2023

Languages

Twi (native) | English

Projects

- Student Management System. Tools: Django, Next JS, Git, and PostgreSQL
- Exam+. Tools: HTML, Django, Bootstrap, CSS, SQLite, Git, and JavaScript
- e logging System: Tools: HTML, Django, Bootstrap, CSS, SQLite, Git, and JavaScript
- Fleet Management System: **Tools**: HTML, Django, Bootstrap, CSS, SQLite, Git, and JavaScript
- Transcript Request System: **Tools**: HTML, Django, Bootstrap, CSS, PostgreSQL, Git, and JavaScript

References

- Eben Allen Tetteh, Senior Systems Analyst Kumasi Technical University
 Mail: allen.tetteh@kstu.edu.gh Tel: 0242310863
- D. L. Lamptey (M. Sc., Alta, Canada), Former Ag. Provost, ANGUTECH
 Mail: danlamptey@gmail.com Tel: 0244050453
- Tattrah, Leo Paapa (MPhil. Computer Science), Lecturer at KsTU
 Mail: leo.paapa@gmail.com Tel: 0246893416